Make way, please.
クラスメートは譲る
Sorry.
すみません。
I'm in a hurry for class.
私は急いで授業をしなければなりません。
It's okay.
わかった
Thank you.
ありがとうございます。
Chengcheng,
クリアー
your wound is deeper this time.
今度は傷が深い
I've prescribed some more anti-inflammatory medicine.
消炎剤を多めに処方しました
Remember to take them regularly.
時間通りに食べることを覚えています
Thank you.
ありがとうございます。
Senior, how do you know that
兄弟子さん、どうして知ってるの？
I don't eat cilantro?
私は香菜を食べません。
Zhu Jiafa told me.
ジュガファが教えてくれた
Senior Jiafa is so kind to me.
足し算さんは私にとても親切です。
All right.
いいでしょう
I saw you taking pictures with your family
今朝私は校門の前で
at the school gate this morning.
あなたがあなたの家族と写真を撮っているのを見ました
Why didn't you take a picture?
どうして撮らないの?
That’s my father and my aunt.
それは私の父と私のおばさんです。
When the freshmen checked in,
新入生が到着した時
I was the only one in the class
私はクラスで唯一
who checked in by myself.
自分で届けに来た
Many people took photos
たくさんの人がいました
at the school gate at that time.
校門で写真を撮る
But everyone was shooting
でもみんなは
with the whole family.
家族みんなで撮った
I didn't really want to take pictures
私は一人で
alone at that time.
当時はあまり撮りたくなかったのですが
After the school year started,
学校が始まったら
I thought it was a bit too touristy
また校門の前で写真を撮っているような気がします
to take photos at the school gate,
ちょっと観光客すぎて
so I didn't take them either.
だから撮ってもいない
So
そう思うと
it seems that I really haven’t
確かにまともではないようだ
taken any serious photos at the school gate.
校門で写真を撮ったことがある
Where are we going?
どこへ行きますか
Take you to take pictures.
写真を撮りに連れて行きましょう
Great.
いいですね
Good.
よし
This one is beautiful.
これはきれいだ
Thank you, Senior.
ありがとうございます
You’re welcome.
大丈夫だ
Let’s go.
行こう
Happy Mid-Autumn Festival.
同級生の秋夕の楽しみ
Taste the mooncake.
月餅を味わう
Taste the mooncakes made by the school.
学校で作った月餅を食べてみる
Happy Mid-Autumn Festival.
同級生の秋夕の楽しみ
Try our school's homemade mooncakes.
学校手作りの月餅を食べてみる
Thank you.
ありがとうございます。
I'll take it for him. Thank you.
私が取ってあげましょうありがとう
Okay, happy Mid-Autumn Festival.
良い中秋節の楽しみ
Happy Mid-Autumn Festival.
中秋節おめでとう
Ham flavor,
雲足の匂い
egg yolk and lotus paste flavor.
卵黄蓮蓉味
Which one do you like, Senior?
兄弟子さんはどれが好きですか。
I don't eat mooncakes. You eat.
私は月餅を食べないから、食べてください。
I actually used to
私は実は昔
love festivals.
特にお祭りが好きです
Because when it comes to the festival,
祝日になると
I had all kinds of reasons
私にはいろいろな理由がある
to ask my parents
パパとママと
for gifts and pocket money.
プレゼントだ小遣いだ
But then they got divorced,
しかし彼らは別れました
and I don't like the festivals anymore.
私は好きではありません
Because I didn't know
私は知らないから
where to go.
どこへ行けばいいの
Don’t like.
いやだ
When I was young, on the Mid-Autumn Festival,
子供の頃は中秋節になると
my family
私たち家族はすぐに
went to the top of the mountain to enjoy the moon.
山頂へお月見に行く
There was nothing really interesting.
実は面白くもない
Our mountains are not high
私たちのところは山も高くない
and there were many people.
人も多いし
It was full of barbecue stalls and small stalls.
バーベキューや屋台ばかり
So noisy.
がやがや騒ぐ
It was the same every year.
毎年そうです
So I got used to it.
慣れてきた
Then my parents got divorced,
それから両親は別れた
and I didn't want to spend the Mid-Autumn Festival,
私は中秋節を考えたことがありません
let alone eat mooncakes.
月餅はもっと食べたくない
Senior,
兄弟子
let me take you to a place.
どこかに連れて行ってあげよう
Where?
どこへ行きますか
Here we are.
着きました
It's so beautiful here.
ここは本当にきれいだ
How did you find this place?
どうしてここを知ってるの？
Once I escaped from self-study at night
ある時私は夜の自習から逃げた
and wandered here.
ここまでぶらぶらしていた
Usually there are few people here.
普段はここも人が少ないですね
Come with me.
ついてきて
From here,
ここで見る
the whole city
都市全体
becomes especially small.
とても小さくなって
Twinkle, twinkle.
ぴかぴか光る
Like a cartoon.
アニメのように
I really like this place.
私は本当にここが好きです。
Unfortunately,
惜しい
there's no moon today.
今日は月がない
Senior, close your eyes.
兄弟子目を閉じて
Why?
何してるの
Just close.
閉じてくれ
No.
閉じない
Don't open .
そっと見開かないで
Don’t be so nervous.
何だよそんなに緊張して
Take it.
しっかりとつかむ
Don’t open your eyes.
開かないで
Now,
私たちは今
we're in a new world.
新しい世界で
Write all your worries
あなたはすべての悩みを
on this piece of paper.
この紙に書いてある
Then put the paper
そして紙を
into a small box
小さな箱に入れて
and lock it with a key.
鍵で錠をかける
The paper airplane in your hand
手持ちの紙飛行機
is the key to this box.
この箱の鍵です
Now raise your arm,
今腕を上げて
listen to my command,
私のパスワードを聞いて
and then fly the paper plane out
力いっぱい紙飛行機を
with all your might.
飛び出す
Then your worries
あなたの悩みは
will float away
紙飛行機と一緒に
with the paper plane
遥か彼方へ
and never come back.
二度と戻ってこない
One,
一
two,
二
Xiaomeng, cheers.
暁夢来
Xiaomeng, I heard from your classmates that
暁夢君の同級生から聞いたよ
you are planning to go abroad after graduation.
あなたは卒業してから外国へ行くつもりです。
Have you decided where to go?
どこかに行きたいと思っていますか。
Not yet.
まだですよ
Maybe
いくつかの学校があります
I'll apply to a few schools.
投げてくれるだろう
What's wrong, Senior?
どうしたの兄弟子
Nothing.
なんでもない
I want to know which school you're going to.
私はあなたがどの学校に行くか知りたいです。
We can go together in the future.
将来は一緒に
Xiaomeng, in fact, I...
暁夢実は私
Senior, I have to answer the phone first.
先輩、先に電話に出ます。
Hello.
おい
What?
何
He withdrew the money again.
彼はまた金を引き出した
I’ve told you many times that
何度言った?
you must hide the money well,
お金はちゃんと隠しなさい
and don't let him know the password.
パスワードは彼に知られてはいけない
Why is it still like this?
どうしてまだ
Hui doesn't have money for tuition, right?
暉さんは学費を払うお金がないでしょう。
How much are in short?
あといくら足りない
Tell him
君は彼に言った
to be a little more aggressive.
彼自身に少し意地を張らせる
He still needs to attend tuition classes.
塾はもちろん通っています
Whenever you eat, you swipe your phone.
食事になると携帯電話をかざす
Are there any rules at all?
さすがにまだ少し規則があるかどうか
When it comes to celebrity gossip,
スターゴシップといえば
there's nothing you don't know.
あなたが知らないものはありません
When it comes to study and future planning,
学習未来計画について話すと
you just make light of it.
あっさりした
I think
どこを見てる?
you have a simple mind
あなたは単純な頭です
but a complicated heart,
複雑な心
spending all your energy
すべての精力を
on things that aren't worth it.
価値のないところに使う
You don't have the ability
大事なことは
to think deeply
少しもない
about the important things.
深く考える能力
Come on, Dad.
いいでしょパパ
Can you let me have a good meal?
ちゃんとご飯を食べさせてくれませんか。
Have some water.
水を少し飲む
Brother,
兄
you've been waiting for a long time, right?
長い間待っていたでしょう
Happy Mid-Autumn Festival!
中秋節おめでとう
It's okay.
大丈夫だ
I probably got it
これはちょうど
in the interest class.
趣味クラスの授業中にぐずぐずしていた
Well, I'm going to go back.
じゃ、先に帰ります
It's been three years,
もう3年になる
you still can't let it go?
君はまだ通れないのか
Chengcheng,
クリアー
thank you.
ありがとう
I'm happy today.
今日は楽しかった
Unfortunately,
惜しい
there's still no moon.
まだ月がない
I also have a gift to you.
私もあなたにプレゼントをあげます。
Close your eyes.
目を閉じて
Why?
何してるの
No.
閉じない
Just close.
閉じて
Don't peek.
覗くなよ
Okay.
わかった
This is the moon I give you.
これが私があなたに送った月です。
Although it's a bit rough.
ちょっとざらざらしていますが
No, I think it's cute.
いやかわいいと思うよ
Are you mocking me?
あなたは私を皮肉っているのですか。
No, I'm not.
私は持っていません
It's really cute.
かわいいね
Let me project it into the sky for you.
天に投げてあげよう
The moon is coming out!
月が出た
Senior,
兄弟子
want some mooncakes?
月餅を食べますか。
Thank you.
ありがとうございます。
Is it good?
おいしいですか
Yes.
おいしい
Are you teasing me as a dog?
犬をからかってるのか?
It's already late. why don’t sleep.
何時になったの?まだ寝てるの?
Why are you...
どうしたの
What happened to your arm?
あなたの手はどうしたの？
I accidentally fell yesterday.
昨日うっかり転んでしまった
Your arm is injured,
手が壊れてしまった
why are you still so happy?
こんなに嬉しいなんて
Did you break your brain?
頭をこわしてしまった
Why are you back?
どうして帰ってきたの
Didn't you go out
あなたは両親ではありません
with your parents?
遊びに行きましたか
I had a fight with my parents,
両親とケンカした
so I came back early.
早めに帰ってきた
But
しかし
even the atmosphere was so tense,
緊張した雰囲気だった
I didn't forget
私は忘れていない
to bring you the souvenirs.
お土産を持って帰ってきてあげる
How's that? Am I nice?
どうですか
True sister.
真の姉妹
At noon today,
今日のお昼
let’s eat in the Guojiao Canteen.
国交食堂で炒め物を食べる
It's on me.
私がおごる
Let's go now.
今すぐ行こう
Let's go.
行く
Wait, I need to take a call.
後で電話に出て
Hello? Senior Jiafa.
おい足し算兄貴
Chengcheng, come over here.
澄まして早く来て
Jianming has escaped from its cage.
建明はケージを飛び出した
Mr. Wang from the breeding room
飼育室の王先生
has gone home on vacation.
家に帰って休みに行った
Jianming hasn't seen him
今建明は何日も続いている
for a few days in a row,
彼に会えない
so it is anxious.
気持ちが少し焦りますね
Okay, I'll come over and take a look.
わかった見てみよう
Okay, okay. Come over.
いいですよ。じゃ、来てください。
Senior, well,
兄弟子
is everyone in the lab?
実験室はみんないますか。
Yes, we're all here.
いるよみんないるよ
Is Senior Xiao also there?
肖さんもいますか。
Yuhe? Yuhe is here.
肖小肖がいますね
It's useless even if he's here.
彼がいても無駄だよ
He didn't feed Jianming.
彼は建明にえさをやったことがないよ
Okay, okay. Come on, come on.
よし、じゃあ来てくれ
Waiting for you.
待っててね
Who is it?
誰だよ
Chengcheng.
クリアー
Last time Jianming escaped,
前回建明が飛び出した
it was thanks to Chengcheng.
澄んだおかげで
She has experience.
彼女は経験がある
Let her help out.
彼女に手伝ってもらいましょう
No, I can handle it myself.
自分で処理する必要はありません
Really?
マジかよ
Yes.
本当に
I'll fix it for you right now.
今すぐ解決してあげる
Come on, get out of the way.
どいて
Senior.
兄弟子
Senior Xiao.
肖さんの兄
Senior Xiao was hit by Jianming.
肖さんは建明に壊された
How is it?
どうした
He's still in there.
まだ中にいるよ
Jianming hit him.
建明に壊された
I can't handle it.
私にはわからない
Are you okay?
あなたは大丈夫ですか
Did you get scratched?
掻かれてないでしょ
I'm fine.
大丈夫だ
Close the door.
ドアを閉める
Oh, my God!
なんてことだ
What are you doing? So noisy.
何をしているんだ
What are you doing?
何をする
Jianming.
建明
Look.
ほら
Jianming is usually good.
建明はいつもおとなしい
It is splashing water.
水をかけた
Hurry up!
急げ!
Today Jianming is really...
建明今日は本当に
Chengcheng, are you okay?
澄澄大丈夫か？
I'm not cold.
寒くない
Go back to the dormitory.
寮に帰りましょう
That monkey...
その猿
Go back.
帰りましょう
Go.
行こう
Well...
これ
How...
どのように
How about?
そうでなければ
Jianming is really...
この建明は本当に
There is a fly.
ハエがいる
Should I go?
まさか私が行くのか
Okay!
よし
Is it just a monkey?
猿じゃないか
Prof..
せんせい
Jianming, you can't do this.
そんなことはできない
Put it down.
ドロップ
Jianming!
建明
Are you crazy?
気でも狂ったのか
You... you're for real!
君は本気だ
Prof. Du.
杜先生
Come on!
さあ来い
Fuck you!
あなたへ
Prof. Du, are you okay?
先生は大丈夫ですか。
Hurry up!
急げ
Go get the keeper.
飼育員を探しに行く
Okay, let’s go.
しっかり行って
Don't all go.
みんな行かないで
Come back one.
戻ってきて
Mr. Wang from the breeding room
飼育室の王先生
has gone home on vacation.
家に帰って休みに行った
Jianming hasn't seen him
今建明は何日も続いている
for a few days in a row,
彼に会えない
so it is anxious.
気持ちが少し焦りますね
Mr. Wang's clothes.
王先生の服
Mr. Wang's keys.
王先生の鍵
According to my observation,
私の観察によれば
Jianming is most sensitive
においと音を明らかにする
to smells and sounds.
最も敏感である
Play Jianming's
建明を再生
favorite cartoon
大好きなアニメ
to attract its attention.
注意を引く
The clothes
服の上
have Jianming’s familiar smell,
建明になじみのあるにおいがする
and the keys have its familiar sound.
鍵には建明のよく知っている声がある
Just as I expected.
案の定私の予想通り
It's done!
成功を収める
You’re back.
お帰りなさい
Whose clothes are you wearing?
この服は誰のですか。
What's going on?
何があった?
This style looks familiar.
このデザインはちょっと見覚えがありますね。
Is it a man
どなたか
named Xiao's?
肖さんは男ですね
I knew it.
私は知っている
When I left,
私が行った時
you two were acting weird.
君たち二人は変だ
Is there something going on between you?
お二人には事情があるのではないでしょうか。
What's going on with you and Xiao Yuhe?
あなたとショー宇河はどうしたのですか。
Tell me. Tell me.
言ってくれ
Why are your underwear transparent?
この下着はどうして透けているの。
No wonder Xiao Yuhe
私はショー宇河と言った
gave me his jacket.
どうやってコートを着てくれますか。
I'm too ashamed. I don't want to live anymore.
私は死んでしまった。私は生きていない。
You mean that
あなたは
Xiao Yuhe knew that
ショー川は知っている
your clothes were wet,
あなたの服は透けている
so he took off his jacket
彼は自分のコートを
and gave it to you?
脱いで着てあげる
Is this the Xiao Yuhe
これはあなたの前に
you told me about before?
私に言ったショー川ですか。
He's changed his mind for you?
彼はあなたのために生まれ変わった
What kind of idol drama is this?
これは何のアイドルドラマのストーリーですか。
This is so romantic.
これはロマンチックすぎるだろう
Do I believe in love again?
まさか私はまた愛情を信じました
That's great.
本当によかった
Look.
ほら
Yes.
そうだ
The most important part
最も重要な一環
is the new love skills
脚本から学んだ
learned from the script.
新しい恋愛テクニック
The hero saves the beauty.
英雄救美
Hello, Senior Xiao.
肖さんは先輩がいい
Let's go.
行こう
Are you okay?
あなたは大丈夫ですか
Yes, I just have a cold.
大丈夫だ風邪気味だ
It is cold these days.
この2,3日は気温が下がった
Put on more clothes, don't catch a cold.
風邪引かないようにたくさん着てね
Where's your jacket?
あなたのコートは?
I left it in the lab.
実験室に落ちた
Do you need to go back and get it?
取りに戻りますか
No, let's go.
急いで行かなくてもいいでしょう
Let's go then.
行くぞ
Let's go.
スタート
Get on my beloved bike.
大好きな自転車に乗って
Is the power of love so great?
愛情の力ってこんなに偉いのか
Su Chengcheng can get up by herself
蘇澄澄は目覚まし時計を使わない
without an alarm clock.
自分で起きられるようになった
Li Meizi,
梅の実
I...
私
I got his jacket dirty.
私は彼の服を汚した
Don’t worry, it's not obvious.
大丈夫かどうかは明らかではない
Obvious, it’s obvious.
明らかにどうして明らかではありません
Come down quickly.
早く降りて
Go with me to wash the clothes.
私と一緒に洗濯してください。
Kill me
私を殺して
to cheer you up.
二人の興を添えてやろう
Meizi, Li Meizi.
梅すもも
Li Meizi, Meizi, Li Meizi.
李梅梅梅梅李梅
Meizi, Li Meizi, Li Meizi.
梅すももすももすもも
Li Meizi.
梅の実
Okay.
私は降ります
Hurry up.
早く早く早く
Put more clothes in it.
もっと持ってきて
One piece won't get the machine running.
1枚では動かせない
That’s enough.
もう十分だ
Why are they all white?
どうして白いんだろう
I'm afraid that
他の服が怖い
if the other clothes lose color,
万が一色が落ちたら
it will be stained.
これ以上染めてしまった
Disgusting.
吐きました
Show your love here.
秀恩愛はここに来た
Show off by washing clothes.
洗濯をしてもショーができる
The lab has a temporary meeting.
私の実験室は臨時に会議を開く
I have to go there.
私は一度行ってみなければならない
When the laundry is done,
洗濯が終わった
please help me take it out to dry.
出して干してくれないか。
Okay.
よし
Don't forget.
忘れないでね
Don't worry.
安心して
I feel like
これを感じる
the left brain is used to listen to language
左脳は言葉を聞いているようだ
and music.
音楽と
Really?
そうですか
Yes, the left ear...
左耳に
Two people.
二人
Senior,
兄弟子
I was going to return the clothes to you.
服を返したかったのに
But it's a little bit dirty.
でも上が少し汚れていて
Can I wash it
きれいに洗ってもいいですか。
and then bring it back to you?
持ってきて
Okay.
行
What's wrong with you?
どうしたの？
Did you give me your jacket yesterday,
あなたは昨日
and you got cold?
服を自分で凍らせてくれた
No, I'm allergic to pollen.
私の花粉アレルギーはありません
Isn't it autumn now?
今は秋じゃないですか
Chrysanthemum.
菊の花
There are no chrysanthemums in our school.
私たちの学校には菊がありませんね。
Osmanthus.
モクセイの花
There is no osmanthus either.
モクセイもいませんね
Newly planted osmanthus? Where?
新種はどこですか。
We're all here now.
みんな大差ないだろう
Okay.
行
Before we start,
それは正式に始まる前に
let me tell you
私はまず皆さんと
one little thing.
ささいなことを言いましょう
Last week, I went to Shanghai with your senior sister
先週はあなた方の先輩と
to attend a meeting.
上海に行って交流に参加した
I accidentally mentioned
無意識にね
the love experiment
私たちの実験室についてお話ししました
in our lab before.
前の実験が好きだった
The experiment
ショウさんと蘇澄澄さんです
Yuhe and Su Chengcheng did.
その実験をしました
Many people are interested in it,
興味を持っている人は少なくない
and hope that
私たちのこの実験が
our experiment
下に降り続けることができます
can be extended further.
伸ばして
Because
既存の
in terms of the current technology,
科学技術レベルで言えば
it is indeed impossible to define liking.
好きは確かに定義できない
But it doesn't prevent us
でも邪魔しない
from observing it
私たちは違う角度から
from different angles.
それを観測する
I have found a small direction.
私は小さな方向を探しました
To study the difference in brain activity
男女の両性を研究する
between men and women
ロマンチックな情報を加工するとき
when processing romantic information.
脳領域活動の違い
In this way,
そうしたら私たちに
we can accumulate some data,
データを蓄積する
which is also
私たちの研究
helpful for our research.
とても役に立ちます
At the weekly sharing meeting,
こうして毎週の共有会では
you can share
観測された結果を
your observations
取り出す
with us.
皆さんと共有してみましょう
It's time to start dating at public expense again,
また公費で恋が始まる
and abuse singles openly
やはり学術の看板を掲げている
under the guise of academics.
堂々と犬を虐待する
Actually,
実はね
the most important part
この実験の
is to study the similarities and differences
異性の違いを研究することです
in the activation of different parts of the brain
ロマンチックな情報を加工するとき
during the processing of romantic information by the opposite sex.
活性化脳領域各部の異同
It doesn't have much to do
これは好きですか
with liking.
実はあまり関係ありません
If you are interested,
皆さん興味があれば
just participate in the experiment.
一緒に参加しましょう
Look,
見てみろ
our dean still cares about
私たちの院長はやはりとても思いやりがある
us singles .
私たち独身犬の
Okay, you all go back
よしみんな帰る
and get ready.
準備して
You can divide up into groups, okay?
グループ分けできますよね
Okay.
よし
Okay, let's get back to the subject.
私たちの話は本題に戻ります
Let's discuss
まず検討しましょう
some key points
先週
of our academic research
私たちのこの学術研究の
last week.
いくつかのポイント
Students, you're all so serious.
学生たちはこんなにまじめですね。
Hello, Prof. Du.
杜先生、こんにちは
Go on with your work.
あなた方の忙しいあなた方の
Nothing, I'm here
大丈夫だ見に来て
to check some data
私たちの前のスタジオの
from our previous studio.
いくつかのデータ
Senior Xiao
肖さんの兄
has been using this machine.
この機械を使っていた
Okay, go on with your work.
忙しいでしょう
Okay.
よし
Go on with your work.
君たちは先に忙しくしなさい
Xiao,
ショー
Prof. Du asks you to go to the office.
杜先生はあなたをオフィスに行かせました。
Are you still
あなたは
developing Musk
まだ一人
by yourself in secret?
こっそりマスクを開発する
Why are you doing this?
なぜそんなことを?
Do you still want to
まだ参加し続けたいのか
participate in this year's competition?
今年の試合は
Yes.
はい
Nonsense!
何ですか
You're completely fooling around!
これはまったくでたらめだ
Xiao Yuhe,
肖宇河さん
I'm not stopping you from pursuing your dream.
私はあなたが理想を追い求めるのを止めているのではありません
I hope you
私はあなたを望んでいます
realize your dreams.
自分の夢を実現する
I also hope that
私もいつかは
one day you will become a valuable
あなたは価値のある人間になる
and successful
そして成果のある
researcher.
科学研究者
But have you thought about
でもあなたは考えたことがありますか
what you will face
あなたが今参加するなら
if you go to
この試合は
this competition now?
あなたは何に直面しますか
Don't forget
あなたはいつまで
the incident
忘れないで
happened three years ago,
3年前の出来事
which had a very bad impact.
非常に悪影響を及ぼす騒ぎ
If you go to the competition
もしこの時
at this time,
あなたは試合に参加します
there are many difficulties
困難が多い
that you can't even imagine.
君が考えもしなかったことだ
Even if you think about it,
あなたが考えても
you can not solve it.
あなたも解決できない
Senior,
兄弟子
what’s going on?
いったいどういうことなのか
Several years ago,
先年
Senior Xiao
肖さんは参加しました
took part in a competition.
どんな試合
The robot he made
作ったロボット
lost control on the spot
その場で暴走した
and hurt people.
人を傷つけてけがをした
Crucially, he clashed
肝心なのはスタッフと
with the staff.
衝突が起きた
Then things got worse and worse.
それから動静はますます大きくなった
He even went abroad to study
彼はもっぱら外国へ行った
for a few years.
何年か本を読んだ
He just went back to school this year.
これは今年になってから学校に帰るのではない
Why did the robot go out of control?
ロボットはなぜ暴走するのか
The robot went out of control...
ロボット暴走
I don't know exactly what happened.
具体的なことは私にもよくわかりません
I heard it from someone else.
私は人の言うことを聞いたのです
I really don't know.
よくわからない
Meizi, what's wrong?
梅はどうしたの
What about the other clothes? Are they all there?
他の服は?
Only that one is gone.
それだけではありません
How could this happen?
どうしてそんなことができようか。
Don't worry, don't worry.
焦らないで焦らないで
I'm going back to the dorm.
私は今寮に帰ります。
Don't worry.
焦らないで
Okay, okay, okay.
いいぞ
What happened?
どうしたの
Just now I deliberately set a time
さっきわざわざ時間を決めたのに
to come to pick it up.
取りに来た
When I came over,
そして私が来るのを待っている間に
your clothes
あなたの服
had all been put aside.
もう全部置いてきた
And Xiao Yuhe's jacket
そしてショー川のそれは
was gone.
ありません
Don’t worry, let’s find it.
大丈夫だ探してみよう
I've told you everything.
言うべきことは全部君に言った
In fact,
実はね
I quite understand your insistence.
私はあなたのこのような堅持をよく理解しています
Researchers
科学研究者か?
should have the spirit of
この株を持つべきだ
not being afraid to lose.
負けを恐れない精神
But this is
でも今は具体的に
the situation now.
ここに置いて
I think,
考えてみます
for one thing,
一方でね
the technical difficulty of Musk
このマスクの技術です
is too much
難易度が高すぎる
for you to deal with alone.
あなた一人では対処しにくい
For another thing,
もう一人
I am also very worried about it.
私もとても心配しています
If you participate in this competition,
もしあなたが今回試合に参加するとしたら
if someone
万が一そんなことがあったら
with ulterior motives
下心のある人
digs up what happened back then,
その年のことを掘り起こす
it will be harmful to you
それはあなたとこの実験室に対して
and to our lab.
それは傷ついている
Right?
でしょう
Given your character,
あなたの性格で
even if I ask you
私は今すぐ言います
to give up now,
あきらめなさい
you won't do it.
君もやらない
Well,
あなたのように
let's stop for a while.
じゃ、しばらく止めましょう。
You think about it.
あなたも考えて
I'll think about it too.
私も考えます
When we figure it out,
などと考えてわかりました
then let’s talk about it
時間を見つけましょう
sometime,
もっと話しましょう
and see what we can do about it.
この件を見てどうするのか
But,
しかし
until we come to a conclusion,
結論が出ないうちに
I want you
私はあなたを望んでいます
to put down
機械実験室のドアカードを
the door card of the mechanical lab.
ドロップ
It's okay.
大丈夫だ
Where's Su Chengcheng?
蘇澄ね
She's going to...
彼女は行く
Su Chengcheng has gone back to the dorm.
蘇澄澄は寮に帰った
Senior Xiao,
肖先輩
what's wrong
君はこの蘇澄が
with  Su Chengcheng?
どうしたんですか
She's not active in her studies,
学習意欲がない
but she's lazier than anyone else.
そのサボって走るのは誰よりも速い
Are you done?
終わりましたか
Yes.
言い終わった
Go on with your work.
忙しいな
Whose jacket is this?
これは誰の服ですか。
Here it is.
ここにいるよ